<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Where Humane Agriculture Grows]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Where Humane Agriculture Grows]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/overlook-acres/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 20:22:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/overlook-acres/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PART 1 Curing Pork Belly Into Bacon. DIY Bacon ITS SOO EASY!!!!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>PART 1 Curing Pork Belly Into Bacon. DIY Bacon ITS SOO EASY!!!!</h1><p>Want to have the best bacon you have ever tasted? Well I would recommend you raise your own pig --- but you don't have to do that. Go to your butcher and buy some pork belly, or buy some from a local grass fed farm and take it home to cure.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/5806d2cc9206dd7eca59b5cc91f8cd7fd7422936.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E4HsanRICFs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">46aa606a-ed5b-4d89-aba4-52ff7f910ff6</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 20:21:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How To Butcher A Pig Nose To Tail. TheScottReaProject]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>How To Butcher A Pig Nose To Tail. TheScottReaProject</h1><p>The Ultimate Pig Butchery Video....In this Epic video, i show you How To Butcher A Pig,ready for the table,showing the cuts we use in the butchers shop to achieve the roasting joints, chops, steaks, belly and diced pork and trim for sausage making.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/2c900e2e71ce770098929b22944e87e40c4dacb6.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vrOOwOOJS9Q</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">05ca9afd-f265-4591-92af-05c071bb0091</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 20:21:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img alt="If you don&apos;t want dead trees you need to box them out with welded wire or cattle panels." src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t15.0-10/p160x160/13176702_1741871589391208_384006937_n.jpg?oh=1efe0e8f19900db5acd04f85a521f738&oe=58077410">]]></description>
            <link>https://www.facebook.com/OverlookAcres/videos/1741871419391225/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">fc94b0d3-b47a-4966-841d-652abc0fce03</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 20:21:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Happy Birthday to Jason today. As a gift, i will take care of the feedings today :) I love sharing our crazy farm adventure we call life with you! ~ Sonja</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.facebook.com/OverlookAcres/photos/a.1598941153684253.1073741831.1516069168638119/1728260987418935/?type=3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e051209e-3ab3-4e50-9e94-471ef175e2d2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 20:21:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Make a Raised Garden Bed with block and irrigation.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>How to Make a Raised Garden Bed with block and irrigation.</h1><p>My cousin Bre made a block planter bed and took you all along for the ride! Share this video! : https://youtu.be/BaUXVWQt89c All New Square Foot Gardening: http://tinyurl.com/h5d7rsc Extreme Gardening: http://tinyurl.com/z594f8z Our Social Media: Facebook: www.facebook.com/OverlookAcres Twitter: https://twitter.com/OverlookAcres Website: overlookacresny@gmail.com For all business inquiries please email: overlookacresny@gmail.com</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/76fc26d50140e469436f9955c235ba784efe5349.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BaUXVWQt89c&amp;feature=youtu.be</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9e30fca4-47be-461c-9271-2389619b40bb</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 20:21:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet Levi and Ginger - Giving "Mudder" A Whole New Meaning]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Meet Levi and Ginger - Giving "Mudder" A Whole New Meaning</h1><p>Levi and Ginger - Both are just under two years old. Ginger is a Halter Bred Quarter Horse and came to us as a companion horse for Levi. Levi - the big boy, is a registered paint. Both are expected to be 16HH when done growing - Levi is much stockier.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/556c2d2277cc7d19a5ea54601a63d9cfaf8c7595.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PMJOSZdfaSE</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b68d1a4a-6f95-486a-b1a6-187b1ec9ccf7</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 20:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Food History - Snout to Tail Living (with a recipe)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Food History - Snout to Tail Living (with a recipe)</h1><p>I think you will find with regards to things like bacon and sausage, it actually came from ensuring every part of the animal is consumed or used. Fatback, bacon - all of these undesirable meat cuts were made palatable and consumed - think of scrapple, head cheese, and in the deep south - chitlings - the idea was that nothing went to waste and it was a large part of why pigs became so popular - and still are very popular - in quite a few cultures. The bones can serve a stock or as a source of gelatin - ground up bone meal as used for a number of things and we can't forget bone marrow. The skin could be used for so many different things from a protective layer to help preserve meat not to mention tanned for leather. 60 or 70 years ago and beyond these pigs we are raising today people would have turned a nose up at - simply not enough lard and meat that was waaay too lean. When I recently had a pig done I told the butcher how excited I was to get the lard, particularly the leaf lard. I was really looking forward to rendering the lard. One of the most valuable parts of a pig had always been the lard - the lard could do so much in so many different ways and it really was a vital component to survival well into the 20th century. I was both astonished and befuddled when the butcher came out of his back room with about ten pounds of fresh leaf lard for me. He told me that nobody wants this stuff and that they use what they need for sausage and throw out the rest. WHAT!!! They throw out the most valuable part of the pig? Only in 2016 do we take something like pig lard, that requires very very little rendering to transform it into a valuable product and throw it out. I don’t see anybody throwing away barrels of oil, after all it is a commodity, so what happened to pig fat? Crisco killed the importance of lard and in order for Crisco to be successful they had to engage in millions of dollars worth of a smear campaign against lard. The funny part of the story is that Crisco is rendered from an inedible (and I think maybe even toxic before processing) seed - the cotton seed. When the cotton seed is pressed it creates an inedible red oil - that red oil is then processed substantially - actually it is crystallized (hence the name "Crisco" the Cri is a derivation of crystallized oils needed to make it) and then hydrogenated for preservation -- this machine created white grease was what was allegedly so much better than lard - and the smear campaign worked. It wasn't long before every 1960's kitchen had a can of Crisco and by the 1970 the "canned convenience" generation had taken full hold of the nation. See, in the 1960's your Mom would go to the market and purchase food fresh and locally - probably most days of the week. We had better connected interpersonal relationships back then because of the makeup of the community and the fact that you were out and about everyday running your errands - it was a full time job - as most 1960's housewives (which are becoming harder and harder to find) would attest to - but I suppose that is a discussion for another day. The point is if the 1960's was the fresh generation the 1970's was certainly the canned generation. Everyone was ecstatic about shelf life, convenience and totally ignorant about preservatives, hydrogenated oils, and corn syrup. To make it even better, prices were dropping. The benefit of highly preserved food was that it lasted longer on the shelves, which translated to a longer selling time - which meant that in the big scheme of things it was actually cheaper for the consumer to purchase - and certainly cheaper if you added in shelf life at home and the freedom it gave you from having to go to the market everyday - truly the 1970’s were the beginning of the end of “real food”. As a side note, the 1970’s were also responsible for ushering in the rise of corn syrup and its ultimate replacement of sugar in nearly every item consumed - its worth mentioning that the rise of corn syrup was linked closely to politics, subsidies, and commodity prices but again that is a different conversation. Ok - back from our short detour there down memory lane. We began this discussion talking about certain meat product and their consumption and my point was that if we look at some of these meat products, specifically those from pigs, that we will most likely find their origins in necessity and the importance of utilizing the entire animal. Sausage, for example, was made from parts and pieces that would otherwise be inedible, unpalatable, or both - or maybe just trimmings from better cuts. You can do two things here - you can toss away those bits and pieces or you can throw them in a grinder with a little pork fat, add some spices, some smoke, and in some cases time - and you end up with a fantastically tasty and edible product of value. We discussed the use of the bones, the head, obviously the cuts of meat, and now the scrap pieces and seemingly inedible bits - but what about all that lard?There are two distinctly different types of pig. Lard pigs tend to be short of body length and put on a lot of fat easily. Lard pigs tend to grow more slowly and not as large structurally. Meat or “bacon” pigs have longer bodies and also have higher levels of muscling. These pigs are fast growing and are much larger - like twice the size of their lard relatives. Obviously you can make a bacon pig fat by over feeding it - but we are talking about unadulterated natural tendencies here. (Just as a side note - take a look at the ears of the boar (male pig) below. Do you see those notches? We don’t do it on our farm yet but this is how pigs are marked and identified - with ear notches. Tags are sometimes used but notches last forever).</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/86f1f50d-e931-4566-bcdb-8338dd583432.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/overlook-acres/food-history-snout-to-tail-living-with-a-recipe/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7f709-c3a2-4cf6-b995-cc62f2b83377</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 19:55:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>